He placed top three in the world trading
competition four separate time.
>> Fabio.
>> I wait for the market to show its hand
first and it always does. Draw the
volume profile over the session. Shows
you where the most money traded. That's
the value area. Now the trade. Price
drops below the value area low. Second
it does, your eyes go on the volume
bars. If they are declining, nobody
really selling and the money isn't
following price lower. Then the buyers
step in and form a wall the sellers
can't push through. There's the bubble,
sellers getting absorbed. Price gets
pulled back towards the money. When it
closes back inside the value area and
the volume bars grow again, that's your
long. Stop below the low, target the
value area high, right back into the
money.
>> Fabio is one of the most legitimate
traders, has the best track record by
far. He does trade real order flow.
TradingView doesn't offer real order
flow,
um which kind of stinks. But this
particular version of a strategy that he
trades, we could actually build this
concept into an indicator that we can
use every single day. Let's go try it.
So I went over to luxalgo.com/quant
and then I gave it the exact parameters
that he had for potential signals. And
what I noticed is when you're doing a
real-time volume profile, the value
areas can adjust a lot depending on what
you're trading and the volume. And so
that got me thinking for TradingView
specifically, maybe we just trade the
previous day's value areas. And actually
turned out to be an incredible
indicator. If you go about in the
settings of this indicator right here,
you can actually click to show previous
day's signals or the current day's
signals. And what I have it looking for
is volume to decrease when it exits out
of a value area high or low of the
previous day and then creates a reversal
type setup. In this case, it's an
engulfing candle. And what you would do
is you would end up taking your
position. Once you get that signal,
targeting either a value area low, a
POC, or your own risk. But, let's just
target the most recent level, which is
that POC, and it ends up hitting it
quite perfectly. Now, the other thing I
realized is that this works really well
on the Nasdaq 15-minute chart. And the
only issue is with the 15-minute in this
exact setup is you might not get a trade
every single day. But, when you do get a
signal, these setups are honestly
phenomenal. Look at this long here, stop
below the low, targeting, in my opinion,
the POC ahead, and let's see if it plays
out. Absolutely rips back to the high.
Now, this is nowhere near what Fabio
uses because he uses real order flow and
trades multiple different strategies.
But, it's fun to try to create an
indicator on top of one of his ideas.
But, I'm happy to give you this
indicator for completely free. Just
comment the word profile and I'll send
you a link. Or, you can [music] head
over to the LuxAlgo library and search
value area reversion signals, and it's
right there.